Q1: Do you work for a local dev team or a distributed dev team?
A: By "distributed" do you mean people working remotely from home?

Q2: With "local" I mean everyone is working on-site, opposed to remote with people from
different places (abroad or not)
A: I work for a distributed dev team, with some members working remotely from other cities.

Q3: Do you have any teammates working from abroad?
A: I do not. All of my teammates work directly from [Omitted: country of origin].

Q4: Does your dev team adopt a specific dev methodology such as Agile?
A: Yes, we follow the most standard agile methodologies such as scrum.

Q5: Do you use pure Scrum?
A: Yes, we normally have sprints with fixed duration, daily reunions, sprint reviews and
retrospectives.

Q6: What do you understand as being a code smell?
A: Maybe the specific style of a code? With it following some kind of recognizable framework
or structure.

Q7: Code smell is also known as code anomaly and bad smell
A: I made a mistake then

Q8: So what do you understand about code smells, now that you know some synonyms?
A: I believe that "code smell" refers to recognizable bad practices in coding, which can be
detrimental to a project.

Q9: Are you concerned about adding code smells to the source code you produce?
A: Yes, since these bad practices and add up and snowball into problems for the future
development of projects.

Q10: Do you believe that your teammates share the same concern?
A: Yes, I do. I normally believe that all of my teammates strive to use good practices while
coding. We also review each other's code, so "code smell" normally doesn't make it to the
final product.

Q11: Do you use tools to detect code smells on the code you produce, consume or
maintain?
A: We use tools such as GitLab to review each other's code, so that the code we produce is
readable and understood to everyone on the team.

Q12: Can you specify all the tools you use for this purpose?
A: We use both GitLab and multiple StyleLint plugins to detect bad practices while coding
with TypeScript.

Q13: Do you run these tools while producing code, after the code is done and have to
refactor it and/or in code you consume (for instance, from open source projects)?
A: We run StyleLint while producing code, and after the code is done all of our teammates
review it in GitLab. If there are any issues with the code, we refactor it before publishing.
