Q1: Do you work for a local dev team or a distributed dev team?
A: I work for a distributed dev team.

Q2: Do your teammates work from abroad?
A: Yes, and in fact I myself do too. Some of them work most of the week from an office,
though.

Q3: Does your dev team adopt a specific dev methodology such as Agile?
A: Yes, we do it Agile, though we do not fully implement a more specific framework - we
mostly apply common practices from agile frameworks, like the Scrum meetings.

Q4: Could you explain a little more how this methodology works?
A: Our own flavor of agile work, or specifically Scrum or Agile itself?

Q5: Your own methodology
A: I guess the bulk of our daily work conforms a lot to Agile, particularly Scrum, but due to
the scale and history of the company it has a bunch of peculiarities. An example is that we
don't do 15 minute dailies - our daily meetings simply can't be that short, since they include
an operational section of system maintenance that takes a while to go through.

Another point is that our sprints are almost just nominal - tasks bleed out through sprints and
there are many delivery dates that don't conform to sprint periods. We use them - in the
classic 2 week long format - mostly for planning and management purposes. We also don't
do sprint retrospectives, doing a monthly retro instead.

And, you know what? I was about to say that we don't do the sprint review, but I just noticed
that we implemented something a few months ago that we called "pre-planning" that covers
exactly what should be done in a sprint review. I'll bring that up to my team sometime, haha.

But, yeah, the company is big and old and with that comes a lot of extra formality and long
term planning that does not comply with Agile - we plan the entire year of development
beforehand, we have three-year-plans for the team/product, we write lots of design
documents and other documentation... And there is a layer of operational work that adds
some complexity to it all (like extra meetings).

Q6: What do you understand as being a code smell?
A: From the top of my head, a code smell is a piece of code that points to a potential
problem or underlying issue with that code's design. Also, specifically not a bug or error - the
code works, it is just possibly badly designed. They don't necessarily mean there's
something wrong, but there usually is - and it is generally worth thinking about and doing
some checking if you find one.

Q7: Are you concerned about adding code smells to the source code you produce?
A: Yeah, for sure. I think that even if you don't approach code development/engineering in a
more theoretical manner you'll still eventually learn through practice that code smells exist
and are in fact a strong sign of something funky going on.

Q8: Do you believe that your teammates share the same concern?
A: Yep. It comes up a lot in code reviews. I'd say it is almost an informal requirement for the
selection process for the company.

Q9: Do you use tools to detect code smells on the code you produce, consume or maintain?
A: Yeah, there are internal tools that point that stuff out. Got a couple warnings yesterday for
duplicate strings, though it was a false alarm in that particular case. Still, I'd rather have false
alarms than no alarms at all.

Q10: Other than internal tools, do you use any other known external tools?
A: For code smell detection? I don't think so. I just noticed I was thinking about a specific tool
that runs after you create a code review, but there are also some checks run when we build
our java packages that detect vulnerabilities that also can catch some code smells - and that
one I'm pretty sure is a public library, but I don't recall which one right now. But no, no
external code smell detection tools.

Q11: What are the reasons for you not using code smells detection tools (both for work and
for personal projects)?
A: In personal projects it would be mostly a matter of lazyness - there's no easier setup than
no setup at all, and it is easy to justify to myself that the potential problems aren't worth the
hassle.

On work on the other hand I'd say it is very important to use code smell detection tools and
that it is very much worth the hassle. But to give you an answer, there are concerns against
using external static code analysis tools, specially in big tech companies. We do have one
on my job, it is just an internal one, and that is why - it is worth developing your own tool if
your code is supposed to be that secret.

