Q1: What do you understand as being a code smell?
A: Any form of bad: habit, design or structure in the context of a code and/or the process of
writing the code itself

Q2: Are you concerned about adding code smells to the source code you produce?
A: Yes. Everytime that a code smell can be avoided (there's time to write better), I personally
prefer to stick with a well sanitized code in order to avoid future problems, such as very
commonly: forgetting what that code was about and what it's meant to do, since it's not
properly written

Q3: Do you believe that your teammates share the same concern?
A: Yes, I do believe so. Although many times we have to deal with a not properly maintained
code base; Legacy code, specially the companies first and/or core products tend to have
been written with looser code rules to prioritize delivery speed

Q4: Do you use tools to detect code smells on the code you produce, consume or maintain?
A: Yes. The tools may vary depending on the project, but it's very common to commits and
MRs be subject to a CircleCI pipeline or similar tool in which we include a step that runs a
Linter in the codebase

Q5: Can you specify all the tools you use for this purpose?
A: CircleCI, Github Actions and custom linters for the language, in the case of Golang for
example: golangci-lint

Q6: Do you run these tools while producing code, after the code is done and have to refactor
it and/or in code you consume (for instance, from open source projects)?
A: I only run linters and refactor any code smell that might be pointed out after the code is
done (sometimes, only after the code was tested by the unit tests); I do not run any linting or
any testing whatsoever for code I consume (third party, open source projects, etc.) as part of
a personal policy of not maintaining code that do not belong to me and/or I did not produce.
If I do not trust the code I'm using or consuming, then I shouldn't be using it

Q7: Do you work for a local dev team or a distributed dev team?
A: By "local" do you mean everyone from [Omitted: country of origin]?

Q8: With "local" I mean everyone is working on-site, opposed to remote with people from
different places (abroad or not)
A: I work for a distributed dev team. The team has the option to work from office, but many
employees are not from the same state the office is located (me included)

Q9: Do you have any teammates working from abroad?
A: Not from the development team, but for a period my teams PO was a person that lived in [Omitted: country different from their country of origin]

Q10: Does your dev team adopt a specific dev methodology such as Agile?
A: Yes, it does. An Agile coaching company was hired to train and enforce the Scrum rituals
on the dev cycle of the company

Q11: So you currently use pure Scrum as the dev methodology for your product?
A: Kinda off, it's VERY common for companies and/or teams to have troubles adhering to
the proper Scrum methodology off which most of the times, the problems can be
summarized as: for the lack of time and possibly discipline, some steps and rites of the sprint
cycle are not respected. So we attempt to stick with the Scrum methodology but sometimes
due to time constraints, meetings and rites are neglected in favor of pushing something that
is urgent and/or fixing a bug or some other form of grave issue
