Q1: Do you work for a local dev team or a distributed dev team?
A: Distributed dev team

Q2: Do your teammates work from abroad?
A: Yes

Q3: Does your dev team adopt a specific dev methodology such as Agile?
A: Yes, we use scrum

Q4: Do you use pure Scrum?
A: Yes

Q5: What do you understand as being a code smell?
A: Code smells are small issues or tech debts that point to a bigger problem on a codebase

Q6: Are you concerned about adding code smells to the source code you produce?
A: Yes, but we are currently not using any tools for analyzing it

Q7: Regarding this concern about code smells, even if you don't use tools, do you believe
that your teammates share the same concern?
A: Half of them do. The others, I'm not sure, I'd say no

Q8: What do you believe they think about code smells?
A: We should pay attention to them while creating new features, but not spend too much
resources for analyzing existing code

Q9: Is this what you believe or what you believe your teammates think about the code
smells?
A: That's what I believe they think about it

Q10: You said you didn't use any tools for analyzing code smells. Why not?
A: Not encouraged by the teams I currently work with. This would require some collective
effort for addressing the detected issues

Q11: So do you think the lack of motivation could be the need for a collective effort, in the
end? Are there other reasons not to do so, even in personal projects?
A: Maybe, but I believe leaderships tend to prioritize other good practices first, like testing.
For personal projects, tools like SonarQube usually require some setup that are an overkill
for the project size


