Q1: Do you work for a local dev team or a distributed dev team?
A: Distributed dev team

Q2: Do your teammates work from abroad?
A: Yes

Q3: Does your dev team adopt a specific dev methodology such as Agile?
A: Yes

Q4: What methodology?
A: Currently we use kind of a hybrid scrum and kanban, but our team doesn't have a specific
person to organize that better, so I feel that it could be improved into our project

Q5: Could you explain a little more how this hybrid methodology works?
A: We have 2 week sprints, with daily meetings and only one meeting that kind unifies what
should be the sprint planning and the backlog grooming. We don't have very restrict sprint
scopes, since we work for a startup which sometimes changes their priorities very fast . We
tried before to always create small cards to not have to estimate each one of those with story
points, but considering each one of them to take 1 or 2 days

Q6: What do you understand as being a code smell?
A: From what the own name says, it's parts of some code where smells bad, that potentially
can bring some future bug or future maintainability issues

Q7: Are you concerned about adding code smells to the source code you produce?
A: Yeah, a lot, I understand that adding those can potentially make my life harder in the
future

Q8: Do you believe that your teammates share the same concern?
A: Not all of them

Q9: What do you believe they think about code smells?
A: Maybe they don't see the direct impact that could cause, and they care more about
delivering

Q10: Do you use tools to detect code smells on the code you produce, consume or
maintain?
A: Yes

Q11: Which tool(s)?
A: Sonarqube

Q12: Do you run the tool while producing code, after the code is done and have to refactor it
and/or in code you consume (for instance, from open source projects)?
A: I have sonar lint into my IDE which shows to me code smells, so I fix while I produce my
code. But we have maintenance task to refactor in case we have code smells into our
reports
